well icsi Lombard is in Focus after the
after the board has approved merger of
the company with bti exis General
Insurance business well let me tell you
bti exi is currently ranked 17th in the
entire general insurance space while ICI
Lombard holds fifth position in the
non-life insurance business and as for
the press releas the combined entity
would now emerge as the third largest
non-life insurer in India coming to the
shareholding pattern well its promoter
entity iccf Bank currently holds 51. 9%
stake in icso Lombard and with this
proposed deal taking place uh the
promoter holding will come down to
48.1% while bti and axr together will
hold 7.3% stake in the company also this
acquisition is to a shares B to The
Exchange issue for the same stands at
two shares of ICC Lombard for every 115
shares held by shareholders of B XR
General Insurance in fact in the recent
con call the analyst had flagged off
certain concern concerns on the
valuations of this deal to which uh the
company tried to assuage concerns saying
that they see significant Headroom for
operating leverage and cost
Effectiveness over time in fact they
continue to add that as of now uh the
company does not require any Capital
raise for solvency purposes given the
solvency margins continue to remain
above the uh well above the regulatory
requirements will also let me tell you
that bti EXA uh is predominantly a
player within the motor insurance
segment and going forward icso Lombard
believes that they would they would be
able to leverage on this segment going
forward and currently on a stand loone
basis they hold 9.8% stake uh uh market
share in the entire motor ins motor
insurance and with this deal taking
place the combined market share would
rise to 12% so they definitely believe
that going forward uh bti EXA would be
able to help them in garnering better
market share within the motor insurance
space and also the banker tups uh will
help in the distribution networks also
uh well lastly we also had clsa coming
out with a note on ICS lad saying that
they maintain their byy stands on the
stock with a Target price of 1,560
rupees per share they add that bti XA
merger is near-term EPS diluted but
however they see significant Headroom
for cost optimization they also add that
the rational for merger is strong given
bti EXA in motor segment and with a 120%
combined ratio and 7.9% share dilution
deal will be earnings dilutive but at
the same time the scale and in Synergy
will help icsi Lombard to optimize
expense ratio in future so definitely a
very optimistic stance that they hold of
this merger and icso Lombard so given
all these parameters icso Lombard
definitely uh this motor would provide
required impetus to the company and
given the fact that General Insurance
space lately has seen a lot of traction
this merger will definitely a the growth
momentum